Lee Songtao

Sr. Engineer at Unicore Communications

lst16888@gmail.com

Summary

Name: Lee Songtao (Michael) Gender: Male Birthday: December, 1976 Degree: Bachelor, graduated on 2000, from Hebei Polytechnic University.

Mobile: 13911159620

Email: lst16888@gmail.com or lst16888@hotmail.com

Web: tophacker.github.com

Linux, Vim&Emacs, GDB, C/C++, PC/Embeded.

Windows, VS6.0/VS2008, MFC.

Be familiar with shell, awk, sed, python, lisp, perl.

Proficient in programming with c, c++ and java language.

Expert in designing and programming under win32 and unix platform.

Strong embedded system designing and programming.

Fluent in english reading, listening, writing and speaking.

Experience

Sr. Engineer at Unicore Communications (a subsidiary company of BDStar Navigation)

March 2009 - March 2013 (4 years 1 month)

1.

Designed and implemented the software named DAT(Data Analysis Tool).

2.

Designed and implemented the frame sync. modules for GPS and BD2, and the measurement assembly module.

3.

Answered for the design of the whole architecture of GSP (GNSS Support Package), Implemented the BBO and BBC module, Led team guys to work together to implement the whole GSP.

4.

Manufacture&Testing Tool(PC side).

Answered for the design and coding for the tool, the tool be used to check various HW issues for company's all products(board cards or modules). The tool with the brightnesses that automatic, efficient, cooccurrence, user-defined action.

5.

WinConfig.

Answer for the design and implementation for the tool. The tool be used to do some job like as upgrading firmware, change configuration for company's all products.

6.

Participated in the design of GSP2.0, implemented the following devices: WEB, PVT, RTCMEncoder, did the maintenance for the followings:device base class, device I/O base class and log encoder module.

7.

Participated in the design of IGMAS, implemented the following devices: Rinex, Frame, NavData, ObsData.

Used platforms: Win32, MQX, Linux(PC/Embeded, ARM11).

Used languages: C/C++.

Sr. Engineer at BDStar Navigation

March 2008 - March 2009 (1 year 1 month)

1.

CDU project. a Control and Display Utility for GNSS receiver.

Answer for writing the design document of the whole architecture for the tool, and some key modules' development.

2.

PVT project.

- 1) Led team guys to do PVT source code's optimization and add the error handling mechanism, and wrote correlative documents.
- 2) Wrote software design document for PVT.
- 3) Participated in the design job for satellites' selection algorithm, and implemented the algorithm in C++.
- 4) Participated in the design and coding job for RTCM 's encoding and decoding.

3.

I/O Control project.

Wrote the design document of the software, implemented the whole architecture based multi-tasks, wrote the command scheduler task and the command parser task.

4.

Simulator project.

Answer for the design of the whole architecture of the tool, coding and unit testing. The tool be used to do some synchronization and control job for different satellite signal(GPS and BD) come from a GNSS Simulator.

Used platforms: Win32, MQX.

Used languages: C/C++.

Sr. software engineer at Beijing MicrovisionTechnologies,Inc.

September 2005 - September 2007 (2 years 1 month)

1.

Fininshed sms second filter server that is used to filter the bad information inside sms,. Using Oracle database, c++, multi-thread, MFC.

2

Finished dsmp protocol data packet parsing and statistic server. Based on winpcap, easysoap and CORBA.

3.

Finished wap and mms data packet parsing modules, using wbxml.

4.

In charge of design and development of some critical modules in wireless service quality trace system for China Mobile, such as, ftp testing, voip testing, task manager and scheduler, network transfer, network reconnecting and task resuming test.

Used platforms: Win32. Used languages: C/C++.

Sr. software engineer at Beijing TechFaithWireless Inc.

September 2004 - September 2005 (1 year 1 month)

1.

In charge of requirement analysis and design and development of SUB-LCD module for several handsets.

2.

In charge of requirement analysis and design and development of SUB-WINDOW module for several handsets.

3.

Took part in the development and unit test of phonebook and call history modules for several handsets.

4.

Development experience based arm9.

Used platforms: Linux(Embeded).

Used languages: C/C++.

Sr. software engineer at Novel-Tongfang Information Engineering Co., Ltd.

September 2000 - September 2004 (4 years 1 month)

1.

In charge of the development and test of PSI/SI stream encoder, this is a server program and usually used to be one very important module in the digital TV broadcasting. And develop a test tool to the PSI/SI stream encoder. The PSI/SI stream encoder has lots of customers, included CCTV.

2.

In charge of the design and development of static PSI/SI stream file decoder.

3.

In charge of the design and development of the PSI/SI general information analysis server, this is one very important module in national cable radio and TV monitoring network system of the state administration of radio film and television.

About technology, Oracle database, C++, MFC, multithreading, socket and design pattern.

4.

Took part in the development and unit test of Electronic commerce system platform used by CHINA TELECOM, finished communication middle ware. Programming language is java, database is mysql&oracle, in addition, socket, multithreading, config file and batch file are also used here.

Finished the pressure test tool of Electronic commerce system gateway, about technology, HTTP/HTTPS, timer, socket, multithreading, config file and batch file.

5.

In charge of the design and development of Statistic module of telephone charge statistic platform used by CHINA TELECOM.

In charge of the design and development of some tool classes, such as log, database connecting and string classes, etc..

About technology, Informix database, Unix and C++.

Used platforms: Win32, Unix. Used languages: C/C++, Java.

Skills & Expertise

Linux, VIM&Emacs, GDB, C/C++, PC/Embeded. Windows, VS6.0/VS2008, MFC.

Proficient in programming with c, c++ and java language.

Expert in designing and programming under win32 and unix platform.

Strong embedded system designing and programming.

Fluent in english reading, listening, writing and speaking.

Be familiar with shell, awk, sed, python, lisp, perl. $\,$

Perl

Education

Hebei Polytechnic University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 1996 - 2000

Grade: A

Lee Songtao

Sr. Engineer at Unicore Communications

lst16888@gmail.com



Contact Lee on LinkedIn